A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office of the Vice President, Senior Director, Office Files of Elizabeth Campbell FA702
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office of the Vice President, Senior Director, Office Files of Elizabeth Campbell
1997-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA702
1.2 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Documentation focuses on Africa Foundations Learning Group (AFLG).
- box 1, 1
  - AFLG - Africa Foundations Learning Group - AFLG Agenda/Timeline/Philanthropy Initiative/Program Plan, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 1)
  - Dakar – AFLG, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 2)
  - AFLG Dakar, 1999 February 8 - 11 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 3)
  - AFLG Kenya Community Development Foundation (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 4)
  - Interviews not completed by phone, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 5)
  - AFLG Interview results (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 6)
  - Key Endowment Issues (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 7)
  - AFLG Meeting Notes, 1999 October 1 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 8)
  - Tools and Practices (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 9)
  - AFLG SAGA (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 10)
  - AFLG Tech Assistance Fund, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 11)
  - AFLG Arab Arts Project/Luxor, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 12)
  - AFLG Uthungulu Community Foundation (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 13)
  - AFLG Community Development Foundation Initiative (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 14)
  - Debt Swaps (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 15)
  - AFLG Email/Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 16)
  - FRAO – WARD, 1998-2000 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 17)
  - AFLG – Senegal Meeting, 1999 February (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 18)
  - AFLG Agenda/Schedule/Outline, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 19)
  - RDCFI – Rural Development Community Foundations Initiative - RDCFI Insitute, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 20-22)
  - RDCFI, 2000 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 23)
  - Natural Resource Management in East Asia and Pacific Region, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 24)
  - RCCI – Rural Community College Initiative - RCCI, 1996-1998 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 25)
  - American Association of Community Colleges, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 26)
  - Kellogg/FF Collaboration, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 27)
  - Worldwide Philanthropy Initiative, 1997 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 28)
  - White House Millennium Communities Project, 1999 (Box 1 (SK#42300), Folder 29)
- Appendix A: Cross-Reference: FF Reports Removed
  Arrangement
  The following item(s) were removed from this collection and transferred to the Archives' Reports Collection. Please consult the Library/Archives catalog for access.
  - The Africa Foundations Learning Group Meeting. "Report of the Meeting." Hotel Savana. Dakar, Senegal, 1999 February 8 - 11 (Report 16076)
  - Africa Foundations Learning Group. "Meeting Notes." Winter Palace Hotel. Luxor, Egypt, 1999 November 1 (Report 16672)
  - "Assisting Institutional Capacity for Change: Lessons from the Rural Community College Initiative." Prepared for the Ford Foundation by AACC RCCI Documentation Team. Ron Eller, Ruben Martinez, Cynthia Pace, Michael Pavel. American Association of Community Colleges. Lynn Barnett, Project Director, 1999 March 8 (Report 15743)
  - "Learnings from RCCI staff retreat – August 1998." Submitted by MDC, A nonprofit research firm, 1998 August (Report 15744)
  - Reviewers' Draft. "Strategic Framework for Natural Resources Management in East Asia and Pacific Region", 1999 January (Report 15745)